<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xml:space="preserve" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Tokens All the Way Down: A Money View of Decentralized Finance</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName><forename type="first">Wenbin</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
							<email>w.wu@jbs.cam.ac.uk</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Cambridge Judge Business School</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Cambridge</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Tokens All the Way Down: A Money View of Decentralized Finance</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">BE6589B565F4EF1B4E68428ECE1BE19D</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.2" ident="GROBID" when="2026-03-04T16:13+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<label type="revision">a91ee48</label>
					<label type="parameters">startPage=-1, endPage=-1, consolidateCitations=0, consolidateHeader=1, consolidateFunders=0, includeRawAffiliations=false, includeRawCitations=false, includeRawCopyrights=false, generateTeiIds=false, generateTeiCoordinates=[], sentenceSegmentation=false, flavor=null</label>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Decentralized Finance</term>
					<term>Token Hierarchy</term>
					<term>Money View</term>
					<term>Credit Structure</term>
					<term>Structural Risk</term>
					<term>Composability JEL Classification: G23</term>
					<term>E42</term>
					<term>E51</term>
					<term>G10</term>
					<term>O33</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>DeFi protocols stack derivative tokens atop one another, yet the resulting structure of claims remains unmapped. Applying the Money View framework, we show that DeFi functions as a layered credit hierarchy that mirrors conventional banking: each protocol accepts tokens and issues new claims against them, creating tiers of increas ingly derived assets. By late 2025, each dollar of base assets supported $4.7 of total claims, with lending and staking driving over 80% of this layering. Position in this hierarchy shapes yields. Reported rates rise with tier depth (+2.0 pp per tier, 𝑝 &lt; 0.001) because lending protocols, which pay higher rates, concentrate in deeper tiers. Yet after correcting for this composition effect, yields fall with each derivation step (-2.9 pp per hop, 𝑝 &lt; 0.001), reflecting lower borrowing demand for nested tokens. The tier premium widens during crises, consistent with repricing of upstream dependency risk.</p><p>These findings reframe DeFi's "double counting" problem as a structural risk question and provide a macroprudential metric for tracking systemwide leverage.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>As of late 2025, the Ethereum blockchain hosts over 1.4 million token contracts (EtherScan 2024), DefiLlama tracks nearly 7,000 DeFi protocols across more than 200 1 blockchains (DefiLlama 2024), and total value locked in decentralized finance <ref type="bibr">(DeFi)</ref> exceeds $170 billion. This proliferation has created a dense web of financial claims whose structure is poorly understood. Protocols stack derivative tokens atop one another, creating chains of claims that extend several layers deep. When a user deposits ETH into a staking protocol and receives stETH, then deposits that stETH into a lending protocol and receives astETH, the resulting token is a claim on a claim, a secondorder derivative whose value depends on every protocol in the chain. This recursive nesting of claims is not unique to DeFi: it is the defining character istic of credit systems throughout monetary history. In the "Money View" framework <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Mehrling 2013)</ref>, rooted in Chartalist monetary theory <ref type="bibr">(Bell 1998</ref><ref type="bibr">(Bell , 2001</ref>), the financial system is organized as a hierarchy descending from ultimate money through succes sive tiers of credit instruments, each representing promises to pay in terms of the tier above. Chained claims-bank deposits backed by reserves, securities backed by bank deposits-are not a defect but the very mechanism through which credit systems expand purchasing power. Banks occupy the center of this hierarchy as dealers in money markets, profiting from the spread between tiers <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Mehrling 2011</ref>); Pozsar (2014)'s shadowbanking hierarchy extends the same logic to nonbank intermediaries.</p><p>The parallels with crypto have not gone unnoticed: Gorton and Zhang (2023) draw an analogy with Free Banking Era banknotes, <ref type="bibr">Anadu et al. (2024)</ref> document stablecoin runs, and <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Olk and Miebs (2025)</ref> characterize onchain credit creation as a form of shadow banking.</p><p>A growing literature addresses the measurement challenges of derivative layering. <ref type="bibr">Luo et al. (2024)</ref> introduce Total Value Redeemable (TVR), distinguishing "plain tokens" from "derivative tokens"; <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Saggese et al. (2025)</ref> propose verifiable TVL (vTVL); <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Brigida (2025)</ref> further document doublecounting limitations. These approaches treat derivative layering as a measurement problem, noise to be filtered out. We take the opposite view: each additional tier in the hierarchy corresponds to one layer of rehy pothecation, and the layering is the credit structure itself-analogous to the money multiplier in traditional banking. <ref type="bibr">Aldasoro et al. (2023)</ref> apply the Money View to stablecoins, modeling them as "crypto Eurodollars" whose par settlement depends on liquidity rather than solvency; we extend this logic from stablecoins to the full DeFi ecosystem.</p><p>A complementary strand of work organizes DeFi by protocol function. <ref type="bibr">Schär (2021)</ref> and <ref type="bibr">Auer et al. (2024)</ref> propose protocollayer taxonomies (lending, trading, deriva tives), and <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Werner et al. (2022)</ref> surveys the composability risks that arise when these layers interact. Crisis studies document the consequences: contagion cascading through the Terra ecosystem (Badev and Watsky 2023, <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Briola et al. 2023</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">, Liu et al. 2023)</ref>, deleveraging spirals from collateral liquidations <ref type="bibr">(Perez et al. 2021, KlagesMundt and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Minca 2022)</ref>, and hidden leverage <ref type="bibr">(Aramonte et al. 2021)</ref>. We complement these proto collevel taxonomies by organizing tokens, not protocols, by their position in the credit chain-a shift in unit of analysis that makes the hierarchical nesting composability produces explicit and quantifiable.</p><p>On DeFi yields, <ref type="bibr">Augustin et al. (2022)</ref> document "reaching for yield" reminiscent of traditional credit markets, <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Cornelli et al. (2024)</ref> show that DeFi rates comove with Treasury yields, and <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Kitzler et al. (2023)</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Wu et al. (2025)</ref>, and <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Shu et al. (2026)</ref> construct interprotocol exposure graphs. No existing study decomposes DeFi yields by hierar chical position; we bridge the yield and network literatures by showing that a token's structural distance from base assets is a firstorder determinant of poollevel yield, providing a structural interpretation for the "reaching for yield" phenomenon. This paper makes three contributions. Conceptually, we apply the Money View to the full DeFi ecosystem, extending the literature that has applied it only to stablecoins <ref type="bibr">(Aldasoro et al. 2023)</ref>. The Token Graph makes explicit the layered credit structurewho owes what to whom-providing a structural framework for risk assessment and a macroprudential metric (the layering multiplier) that tracks systemwide leverage in real time. Methodologically, we develop a balancesheet approach to discover token hierarchies automatically from poollevel data, treating every DeFi protocol as a finan cial intermediary holding assets (input tokens) and issuing liabilities (output tokens).</p><p>Empirically, we trace the hierarchy through major disruptions (Terra collapse, FTX bankruptcy, SVB crisis) and show that an embedded yield correction disentangles two channels previously conflated in raw data: a compositional tier premium driven by the changing protocol mix across tiers, and a structural distance discount that survives the correction and widens during crises.</p><p>Section 2 develops the conceptual framework, Section 3 describes the data and methodology, and Section 4-Section 5 present results and discussion.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Conceptual Framework</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">DeFi Protocols as Financial Intermediaries</head><p>DeFi protocols function as financial intermediaries that accept tokens as deposits and issue new tokens as claims against those deposits, mirroring the basic operation of traditional banking. A bank accepts cash and issues a deposit receipt; Aave accepts WETH and issues aWETH. In both cases, the fundamental operation-accepting one asset and issuing a claim on it-creates the tiered credit relationships that constitute a monetary hierarchy. Formal definitions are provided in Section A.</p><p>We observe this intermediation directly in poollevel data. Each liquidity pool corre sponds to one such transformation: a pool record specifies input tokens, output tokens, and total value locked as formalized in Equation 3. The directed edges in our token graph derive from these poollevel observations. As Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">1</ref> illustrates, when a user deposits USDC into Aave, the protocol issues aUSDC as a receipt token, defining a directed edge USDC → aUSDC. Each protocol's inputoutput pairs collectively define the structure of the DeFi ecosystem. Each pool represents one such transformation relationship.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">The Token Hierarchy</head><p>These intermediation relationships give rise to a layered structure. DeFi tokens occupy distinct tiers in a credit hierarchy analogous to the money hierarchy <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Mehrling 2013)</ref>, with each tier defined by its distance from base assets. Tier 0 contains native blockchain assets (ETH, BTC, SOL) and abstract monetary units (USD)-the "base money" against which all other tokens are valued.</p><p>Tier 1 comprises tokens directly derived from Tier 0: wrapped tokens (WETH, WBTC) representing onetoone claims on native assets; fiatbacked stablecoins (USDC, USDT) representing claims on offchain reserves; liquid staking tokens (stETH, rETH) representing staked assets plus accrued rewards; and format conversions within the tier such as wstETH, a nonrebasing wrapper of stETH that the algorithm assigns to Tier 1 via the shortest namecontainment path to ETH. Tier 2 consists of tokens issued by protocols that accept Tier 1 inputs. Lending receipts (aUSDC, cWETH) from Aave and Compound, DEX liquidity pool tokens, and restaking derivatives (weETH, ezETH) fall into this category. Higher tiers contain tokens built on Tier 2, including yield aggregator receipts and structured products. Table 1 provides examples at each tier.</p><p>Formally, a token's tier is determined by its shortest path from any Tier 0 asset, as Equation 5 defines. The crucial implication is that risk is cumulative: a Tier 3 token inherits the risks of every protocol in its derivation chain-Tier 2, Tier 1, and ultimately Tier 0.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Tier Transitions and Credit Creation</head><p>Not all tier transitions are economically equivalent, and the hierarchy provides a framework for understanding this. Consider the "double counting" problem in DeFi TVL metrics: when the same ETH appears as WETH in one protocol's TVL and as aWETH in another's, naive aggregation counts the same value multiple times.</p><p>Prior work treats this as a measurement problem to be filtered out-TVR and vTVL, discussed in Section 1. DefiLlama, our primary data source, addresses double counting</p><p>Tier Token Description TVL ($B) 0 ETH Native Ethereum 40.5 0 BTC Native Bitcoin 0.6 0 SOL Native Solana 0.3 1 WETH Wrapped ETH 44.8 1 stETH Lido Staked ETH 29.0 1 USDC USD Coin 15.9 1 wstETH Wrapped stETH 9.2 1 WBTC Wrapped BTC 7.0 1 USDT Tether 6.0 2 weETH Wrapped eETH 15.4 2 aWBTC Aave WBTC 4.3 2 aUSDC Aave USDC 3.8 2 cWETH Compound WETH 1.2 3 aweETH Aave weETH 6.4 3 awstETH Aave wstETH 5.3 3 spwstETH Spark wstETH 2.1 4 aEzETH Aave ezETH 0.4 4 aTETH Aave tETH 0.2 Table 1 | Example Tokens by Hierarchy Tier (TVL as of Q4 2025). by excluding 15 protocol categories from chainlevel TVL aggregation, an ad hoc approach that cannot track individual token flows (DefiLlama 2022). But applying the Money View reveals that "double counting" conflates three economically distinct tier transitions, each with different implications for risk: Format conversion (e.g., ETH → WETH). Wrapping a native asset into an ERC20 token creates no new purchasing power and involves no credit risk beyond the wrapping contract. The holder of WETH has an identical economic claim to ETH, a change in form, not substance. We include it because downstream protocols accept WETH but not ETH, making WETH the operational unit of DeFi. Claim creation via staking (e.g., ETH → stETH). Liquid staking expands the protocol's balance sheet: Lido holds staked ETH as assets and issues stETH as a liability. The new claim circulates freely as collateral in downstream protocols, though the underlying ETH remains locked in validation rather than being redeployed. This is analogous to a moneymarket deposit: the balance sheet expands and a new liquid claim is created, even though the underlying asset is not lent out. Claim creation via lending (e.g., WETH → aWETH). Lending takes balancesheet expansion a step further: the depositor holds aWETH while a borrower obtains WETH to deploy elsewhere. The same underlying asset now supports two simultaneous circulating claims. Successive depositborrowredeposit rounds produce the layering that constitutes DeFi's credit structure. These three categories capture the canonical tier transitions, but the 2024-2025 DeFi landscape has introduced additional mechanisms that extend the taxonomy. Restaking (e.g., stETH → eETH via EigenLayer) extends staking security to additional Actively Validated Services (AVS), introducing correlated slashing risk across multiple operators -a form of systemic risk absent from simple staking. Our methodology correctly classifies restaking derivatives (weETH, ezETH) at Tier 2, though the risk profile is qualitatively different: a Tier 2 restaking token may carry greater cumulative risk than a simple Tier 2 lending receipt, since slashing can propagate from any AVS operator. Yield tokenization (e.g., stETH → PTstETH + YTstETH via Pendle) splits yield bearing assets into fixedrate principal (PT) and variable yield (YT) components. The namecontainment heuristic correctly identifies these tokens (e.g., PTstETH contains "stETH" as a substring after prefix stripping), and the graph assigns them at the appro priate tier. However, PT and YT have very different risk profiles from lending receipts at the same tier: PT represents a fixedrate claim while YT provides leveraged yield exposure, and Pendle's YT mechanism was widely used for leveraged points farming in 2024. Delta-neutral synthesis (e.g., ETH + short perpetual → USDe via Ethena) creates synthetic stablecoins through hedged positions on centralized exchanges (with off exchange custody via Copper and Ceffu). USDe is correctly classified at Tier 1 as a USD derivative, but introduces centralized exchange counterparty risk qualitatively different from USDC's banking custody risk or DAI's onchain overcollateralization. These newer mechanisms extend but do not invalidate the threecategory taxonomy; our graphtheoretic tier assignment handles them correctly, though interpreting tier position as a homogeneous risk measure requires the caveats above. The traditional money multiplier analogy applies most directly to lendingdriven transitions. If the Money View is correct, we expect lending protocols to dominate uppertier transitions, as each lending step creates new claims analogous to deposit creation in banking. We verify this prediction in Section 4.</p><p>We define a layering multiplier, total mapped TVL divided by Tier 0 TVL as formalized in Equation <ref type="formula" target="#formula_2">6</ref>, measuring how many dollars of claims exist per dollar of base assets.</p><p>This metric is broader than the banking money multiplier: it captures all forms of derivative layering, not only credit creation. We decompose it in Section 4 to distinguish contributions of wrapping, staking, and lending.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.4">Hypothesis Development</head><p>If DeFi is indeed organized as a credit hierarchy, the Money View generates testable predictions about how yields should vary across tiers. Each additional tier introduces incremental smart contract risk, liquidity risk, and counterparty risk, so theory predicts that yields should compensate for these accumulated exposures.</p><p>Two channels could link hierarchical position to yields, and they need not operate in the same direction. First, a compositional gradient: the Money View predicts that staking protocols dominate lower tiers while lending protocols dominate upper tiers. If differ ent protocol types offer different yield structures, yields may vary with tier because of the changing protocol mix at each depth. Second, structural distance (derivation hops from base assets) may independently affect yields: more deeply nested tokens attract fewer borrowers, leading to lower utilization rates and consequently lower algorithmically determined lending rates. These two channels can operate in opposite directions: the compositional gradient predicts higher yields at deeper tiers (lending offers higher rates than staking), while structural distance may predict lower yields (borrowing demand declines with derivation depth).</p><p>Hypothesis 1 (Yield-Hierarchy Association): Yields vary systematically with hierarchical position, after controlling for pool characteristics and market-wide yield fluctuations.</p><p>We decompose Hypothesis 1 into two subpredictions. H1a (Compositional Chan nel): the tieryield gradient operates through the changing protocol mix across hierarchy depths, so controlling for protocol type substantially attenuates it. H1b</p><p>(Structural Distance): conditional on protocol type, derivation hops from base assets independently predict yields. Our empirical strategy, progressive fixed effects and comparison between discrete tier and graph distance, distinguishes these channels.</p><p>The Money View further predicts that sensitivity to upstream risk should be time varying, reflecting the state of market liquidity.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Hypothesis 2 (Countercyclical Premium):</head><p>The tier yield gradient increases during market stress, consistent with repricing of upstream dependency risk.</p><p>During crises, the survival constraint <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Mehrling 2011</ref>) becomes binding: participants demand higher compensation for holding claims that depend on multiple upstream protocols, or sell those claims to move toward base money. This should manifest as elevated tier coefficients during episodes such as the Terra collapse, FTX bankruptcy, and SVB crisis.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Data and Methodology</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Data Sources</head><p>Our analysis draws on DeFi data from DefiLlama (DefiLlama 2024), covering over 7,000 protocols across 200+ blockchains. We collect data on approximately 18,000 liq uidity pools, including input and output tokens, TVL in USD, annualized percentage yield (APY), and blockchain and protocol identifiers. The complete tier assignment algorithm is provided in Section A.6.</p><p>DefiLlama aggregates TVL through protocolspecific "adapters" contributed by protocol teams, introducing reporting heterogeneity. <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Saggese et al. (2025)</ref> estimate that only 46.5% of aggregate DeFi TVL can be independently verified onchain. Our tier assignment depends primarily on the topology of token relationships rather than TVL magnitudes, providing partial insulation from reporting errors.</p><p>For lending protocols (Aave, Compound, Morpho), receipt tokens are not always explicitly recorded. We infer receipt token symbols using protocolspecific naming conventions (e.g., WBTC in Aave v3 generates aWBTC; in Compound, cWBTC). This inference step is essential for mapping token transformation relationships in lending markets.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Token Graph Construction</head><p>We construct a directed graph 𝐺 full = (𝒳︀, ℰ︀ full ), formalized in Equation <ref type="formula">4</ref>, where ver tices represent tokens and edges represent transformations. An edge from 𝐴 to 𝐵 exists if some protocol accepts 𝐴 and issues 𝐵. Each edge carries metadata including protocol, blockchain, and TVL. The resulting graph contains approximately 10,200 nodes and 12,100 edges.</p><p>The graph is predominantly acyclic: 79 cycles (0.65% of edges), with cycleinvolved TVL of just 0.03% after excluding the trivial ETH ↔︎ WETH wrapper. Cycles are resolved by assigning the minimum tier from the shortest path to Tier 0; see Section A.7.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Tier Assignment</head><p>Rather than manually specifying base tokens, we discover the hierarchy from graph topology using a balancesheet approach grounded in the Money View: each non trading DeFi protocol holds assets (input tokens) and issues liabilities (output tokens), defining a derivation relationship.</p><p>We construct a derivation graph from the full token graph by retaining only edges that represent genuine derivation-where a protocol transforms an input token into a structurally new output token. We exclude trading protocols (DEXs, derivatives, bridges) since these facilitate exchange rather than token creation, and filter edges that represent borrowing rather than derivation (e.g., crosscollateral lending, basetobase lending). We supplement the graph with CDP minting edges not captured by yield data (e.g., MakerDAO: WETH→DAI; Liquity: WETH→LUSD) and synthetic edges inferred from token naming conventions. The complete filtering and construction procedure is detailed in Section A.6. Tier 0 tokens-the "base money" of the DeFi hierarchy-are identified as tokens with zero indegree in the derivation graph, subject to minimum connectivity and TVL thresholds (outdegree ≥ 3, source TVL ≥ $1M). This yields 169 base tokens, including native blockchain assets (ETH, BTC, SOL), fiatbacked stablecoins (USDC, USDT), and major governance tokens. CDPminted stablecoins (DAI, FRAX, LUSD, GHO) are correctly classified as derived tokens (Tier 1-2), consistent with their position in Mehrling's hierarchy as credit instruments backed by crypto collateral. From Tier 0, we propagate assignments via TVLweighted BFS: Tier(𝐵) = Tier(𝐴) + 1 for each derivation edge, with shortest paths and TVL as tiebreaker. Sensitivity analysis across 25 parameter configurations confirms that core tokens appear as Tier 0 in all cases (Section B).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4">Panel Specification and Identification</head><p>We construct a panel of poolmonth observations from February 2022 through December 2025. From the pool universe described above, we (i) retain pools with tier 0-3 assignments; (ii) require nonmissing APY and TVL; (iii) exclude pools with TVL below $1,000; and (iv) winsorize APY at the 1st and 99th percentiles. </p><p>where 𝜇 𝑝 and 𝜈 𝑐 represent protocoltype and chain fixed effects. These controls absorb confounding variation if tier proxies for protocol type or chain characteristics.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Graph distance.</head><p>As a complementary measure, we replace the discrete tier variable with graph distance: the shortestpath length in integer hops from each pool's primary token to the nearest Tier 0 token. While tier is a coarse fourlevel variable (0-3), graph distance captures finergrained structural variation (Pearson correlation with tier: 0.66).</p><p>Graph distance is available for 93% of the panel (𝑁 = 1,900,190).</p><p>Standard errors. We cluster at the pool level <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Petersen 2009)</ref>.</p><p>Identification. Tier assignment may correlate with unobserved pool characteristics.</p><p>Our primary defense is saturated controls: protocoltype and chain fixed effects ensure the tier coefficient captures withincategory, withinchain variation. Additionally, tier assignments are timeinvariant (derived from the fullsample graph), mitigating reverse causality-and persnapshot rediscovery confirms that this assumption is em pirically justified (Section B.1). Any measurement error in tier classification produces attenuation bias. We also exclude liquid staking pools as a subsample check and conduct a randomization inference test (1,000 permutations of tier labels; Section E).</p><p>Event regime analysis.</p><p>To test Hypothesis 2, we estimate Equation 1 separately for predefined event windows: the Terra collapse (May-July 2022), FTX bankruptcy (November 2022-January 2023), SVB crisis (March-May 2023), and Bitcoin ETF event (January-March 2024). 0 20 40 TVL ($B) PYUSD USDS USDT Other USDC ETH $1.5B $4.8B $6.0B $7.0B $15.8B $40.0B a Tier 0 0 10 20 30 TVL ($B) AUSDT MPLUSDC SUSDS MUSDC WETH Other STETH $1.6B $3.0B $4.2B $4.8B $8.8B $25.3B $27.4B b Tier 1 0 10 20 30 40 TVL ($B) AWETH RETH AWBTC AWSTETH WEETH WBETH Other $3.6B $4.3B $4.3B $5.3B $8.1B $10.5B $30.3B c Tier 2 Fig. 2 | Token Composition by Tier. Panels show the largest tokens by TVL at each tier of the hierarchy: (a) native assets at Tier 0, (b) wrapped and staked derivatives at Tier 1, and (c) secondorder derivatives at Tier 2.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Token Graph Structure</head><p>Trans. TVL Stake Lend DEX Other T0→T1 $72.3B 40% 33% 5% 22% T1→T2 $57.1B 45% 46% 3% 6% T2→T3 $8.6B 0% 99% 1% 1% T3→T4 $5.1B 0% 99% 0% 1%</p><p>Table 3 | Protocol Type Distribution by Tier Transition (share of TVL by protocol category).</p><p>size from Tier 0 to Tier 2, combined with the growing "Other" residual, illustrates both value attrition and increasing fragmentation at higher tiers.</p><p>To understand which types of intermediaries drive each transition, Table <ref type="table">3</ref> decom poses value flows by protocol category. A clear pattern emerges. At the lowest transition (T0→T1), staking (40%) and lending (33%) share the role of firsttier intermediary: users either stake native assets or deposit them into lending markets. At T1→T2, both continue to contribute nearly equally (45% and 46%). But by T2→T3, lending accounts for 99% of flows-staking has essentially no role at these depths. This "stake then lend" pattern reveals a progressive financialization across the hierarchy, mirroring the traditional financial system where moneymarketlike instruments (staking) give way to credit intermediation (lending) at greater depth. The pattern also has a direct empirical consequence: because different protocol types dominate at different tiers, any yield gradient across tiers will partly reflect the changing protocol mix, a compositional effect we test explicitly in Section 4.3.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Hierarchy Evolution 2022-2025</head><p>Quarterly snapshots from Q1 2022 through Q4 2025 trace the hierarchy through the Terra collapse, the FTX bankruptcy, the SVB crisis, and the subsequent recovery. 2023 2024 2025 0 20 40 60 80 100 Share of Mapped TVL (%) a Tier 0 Tier 1 Tier 2 Tier 3 2023 2024 2025 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 Layering Multiplier (Total / Tier 0) 3.6× 3.2× 2.8× 2.4× 2.3× 2.2× 2.1× 2.3× 2.6× 3.1× 4.1× 4.0× 4.9× 4.7× Terra FTX SVB BTC ETF b Fig. 3 | DeFi Hierarchy Composition and Layering Multiplier (2022-2025). (a) Tier shares of mapped TVL. (b) Layering multiplier showing deleveraging through crises (3.6 × to 2.1 ×) followed by releveraging (4.7 × by Q4 2025). persistence rather than a static labeling artifact. Panel (b) quantifies derivative layering. As of Q4 2025, the multiplier stands at 4.7 ×, recovered from a postcrisis low of 2.1 × in early 2024. Not all of this layering constitutes credit creation, however. To understand what drives the multiplier, we decompose the excess (4.7 × -1 = 3.7 ×) by protocol type using edge TVL shares as detailed in Section A.5. Lending accounts for 1.7 × (45% of the excess), staking for 1.4 × (38%), and other protocols (including DEXs and yield aggregators) for 0.6 × (17%). Lending and staking together thus account for over 80% of the excess multiplier, with lendingdriven credit creation-the channel most analogous to traditional deposit multiplication-as the single largest component.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Tier Premium and Embedded Yield Correction</head><p>Two complementary measures capture hierarchical position: the discrete tier (0-3) and graph distance (BFS hops to the nearest Tier 0 token). These two measures tell different stories-and an embedded yield correction is needed to disentangle genuine structural effects from a measurement artifact in DeFi yield reporting.</p><p>Table 4 presents tier regressions with progressively saturated controls. The initial result is counterintuitive: the baseline gradient is negative at -0.52 pp per tier, signif icant at the 10% level, indicating that pools at deeper tiers report lower APY. Adding protocoltype fixed effects strengthens this negative effect to -0.72 pp, while chain (1) (2) (3) (4) (5) (6) Baseline 1. Prot. FE 1. Chain FE 1. Both FE Excl. LST Tier Dum. Tier -0.523 * -0.721 * * 0.008 -0.520 * -0.526 * (0.278) (0.292) (0.286) (0.290) (0.291) Tier 1 0.377 (0.484) Tier 2 -1.768 * * * (0.627) Tier 3+ -0.198 (1.163) Controls Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes Time FE Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes Protocoltype FE No Yes No Yes Yes Yes Chain FE No No Yes Yes Yes Yes Observations 2,036,562 2,036,562 2,036,562 2,036,562 2,028,900 2,036,562 𝑅 2 0.005 0.030 0.040 0.059 0.060 0.061 Table 4 | Panel Regression: APY on Hierarchy Tier. Controls: log(TVL), stablecoin indicator. Poolclustered SEs. * * * 𝑝 &lt; 0.01, * * 𝑝 &lt; 0.05, * 𝑝 &lt; 0.1.</p><p>fixed effects absorb it entirely (Column 3). The full specification (Column 4) yields -0.52 pp, marginally significant. The tier dummy specification (Column 6) localizes the pattern: Tier 2 earns 1.77 pp less than Tier 0, significant at the 1% level, while Tier 1 and Tier 3+ are insignificant-a nonmonotonicity that the embedded yield correction below explains. Excluding liquid staking pools (Column 5) has no material effect.</p><p>This negative gradient is puzzling if deepertier tokens carry more risk. Graph distance-a finergrained measure counting the integer hops from each pool's primary token to the nearest Tier 0 token-deepens the puzzle. Each additional hop is associated with -2.15 pp lower APY in the baseline, highly significant and surviving all fixed effects at -1.86 pp under full controls; Section F reports the full results. However, when we include both tier and graph distance in a joint specification, a strikingly different picture emerges: the tier coefficient flips to +1.18 pp while graph distance remains strongly negative at -2.75 pp per hop. The hierarchy thus encodes two opposing channels: a compositional premium (higher tiers contain more lending protocols, which offer higher rates) and a structural distance discount (reported APY declines with each hop from base assets). In singlevariable models these partially cancel because tier and graph distance are correlated (𝑟 = 0.66), explaining the weak negative tier coefficient when estimated alone. The 𝑅 2 of 5.9% is comparable to prior DeFi yield regressions (Augustin et al. 2022); our interest is in the direction and mechanism of structural associations.</p><p>Embedded yield correction. The two opposing channels raise a natural question: is the structural distance discount a genuine economic effect, or does it reflect how DeFi yield aggregators report returns? Platforms like DefiLlama report only the outermost protocol's APY, omitting accumulated upstream returns. For example, a Tier 2 Aave pool holding weETH reports nearzero lending yield, even though the depositor also earns the ≈ 3% staking return embedded in weETH. If deepertier pools systematically omit more upstream yield, the negative graph distance coefficient could be partly or wholly a reporting artifact.</p><p>To test this, we construct an embedded yield correction. For each hierarchy edge (e.g., ETH → stETH via Lido), we extract the creation yield from DefiLlama's singletoken pool data (TVLweighted mean APY). Each token's total embedded yield is the recursive sum of creation yields from Tier 0 upward: embedded(𝑇 ) = 𝑦 create(𝑇 ) + embedded(parent(𝑇 )), with base tokens at zero. Yield data is available for 2,139 of 18,755 hierarchy edges; unmatched edges default to zero, making the correc tion conservative. The corrected dependent variable is APY corrected = APY reported + embedded yield.</p><p>The magnitude of the correction increases monotonically with tier depth: mean embedded yield is 0.13 pp at Tier 0, 0.36 pp at Tier 1, 1.27 pp at Tier 2, and 2.09 pp at Tier 3, confirming that the omission is systematic and grows with hierarchical distance.</p><p>Table 5 presents the core test. In Panel A, correcting for embedded yield attenuates the tier coefficient by 93%, from -0.53 pp to a statistically insignificant 0.04 pp in the baseline and from -0.52 pp to 0.03 pp under full controls. The correction renders the tier coefficient indistinguishable from zero across all specifications, identifying the Original Corrected Original Corrected (1) (2) (3) (4) Panel A: Tier (full sample) Tier -0.525 * 0.037 -0.524 * 0.032 (0.278) (0.286) (0.290) (0.300) Panel B: Graph Distance Graph dist. -2.150 * * * -1.904 * * * -1.862 * * * -1.437 * * * (0.303) (0.312) (0.390) (0.401) Panel C: Joint Model (Full FE) Tier 1.182 * * 2.016 * * * (0.489) (0.505) Graph dist. -2.747 * * * -2.947 * * * (0.569) (0.579) Controls Yes Yes Yes Yes Time FE Yes Yes Yes Yes Proto + Chain FE No No Yes Yes</p><p>Table 5 | Embedded Yield Correction Test. Columns (1, 3): dependent variable is DefiLlama's reported APY. Columns (2, 4): dependent variable is corrected APY (reported + embedded yield). Panel C includes both tier and graph distance. Poolclustered SEs. * * * 𝑝 &lt; 0.01, * * 𝑝 &lt; 0.05.</p><p>negative tier-yield association as a measurement artifact. In Panel B, the graph distance coefficient is far more robust: it attenuates by only 23% under full controls, from -1.86 pp to -1.44 pp, remaining highly significant in both cases. The structural distance discount survives the embedded yield correction intact. In the joint model on corrected APY (Panel C), both channels emerge cleanly: a compositional tier premium of +2.02</p><p>pp per tier and a structural distance discount of -2.95 pp per hop, both significant at the 1% level.</p><p>Together, these results resolve the puzzle. The negative tier coefficient is predomi nantly a measurement artifact: yield underreporting grows with tier depth, so deeper tier pools appear to earn less when in fact they are reporting less of their total return.</p><p>The graph distance coefficient, by contrast, survives the correction with only 23% attenuation, confirming a genuine structural effect. The joint model on corrected APY cleanly separates both channels: controlling for structural distance, each tier carries a +2.0 pp compositional premium (reflecting the higher yields of lendingdominated upper tiers); controlling for tier, each additional hop carries a -2.9 pp structural discount, consistent with lower borrowing demand and utilization rates at greater derivation depth.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4">Crisis Dynamics</head><p>If the hierarchy reflects genuine structural risk, the yield gradient should be time varying-widening when markets reprice upstream dependency risk and narrowing during calm periods. pp during the Bitcoin ETF event, both significant at the 5% level. The Terra and FTX episodes show elevated but insignificant estimates, likely reflecting their shorter event windows. The overall pattern supports Hypothesis 2: the yield gradient widens during stress, consistent with repricing of upstream dependency risk <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Mehrling 2013)</ref>. That the SVB crisis produced the largest spike is particularly revealing-it was the one crisis that cascaded through the hierarchy, from USDC's depeg to every derivative built on it, underscoring how deeply the DeFi hierarchy remains anchored in traditional finance.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Discussion</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Theoretical Implications</head><p>A Tier 3 token such as aweETH depends on the correct functioning of Aave, ether.fi, Lido, and ultimately the Ethereum network. Each protocol in this chain represents an independent point of failure; the hierarchy makes these dependency chains explicit, observable, and quantifiable at ecosystem scale.</p><p>The empirical results support this framework in a nuanced way. The raw data initially suggest that deepertier pools earn less, not more-seemingly contradicting a risk premium story. But the embedded yield correction reveals that this negative tier gradient is largely an artifact of how DeFi yields are reported: platforms like DefiLlama show only the outermost protocol's rate, so deeper pools systematically understate their total return. Once this omission is corrected, the tier coefficient vanishes while the graph distance coefficient remains robust. In other words, the hierarchy contains two distinct economic signals that were previously conflated.</p><p>The first signal is compositional. As the then lend" pattern in Table <ref type="table">3</ref> shows, the protocol mix shifts systematically across tiers-from stakingdominated lower tiers to lendingdominated upper tiers. Because lending protocols typically offer higher rates than staking protocols, this compositional shift generates a tier premium medi ated by protocol type. This supports H1a (Compositional Channel): the tier-yield gradient is mediated by protocol composition.</p><p>The second signal is structural. Even after correcting for embedded yield and con trolling for protocol type, pools that are more hops from base assets in the derivation graph earn lower yields, on the order of 1.4 to 2.9 pp per hop depending on the speci fication. This structural distance discount is consistent with lower borrowing demand and utilization rates at greater derivation depth: deeply nested tokens attract fewer borrowers, depressing the algorithmically determined lending rates that dominate uppertier yields. It supports H1b (Structural Distance) and survives the embedded yield correction with only 23% attenuation.</p><p>The timevarying tier gradient provides further evidence that the hierarchy captures real risk. The compositional premium widens during crises-from 0.61 pp in normal periods to 1.62 pp during the SVB crisis-consistent with the Money View's prediction that upstream dependency risk is repriced when the survival constraint becomes binding <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Mehrling 2013)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">What Grounds the DeFi Hierarchy?</head><p>Applying the Money View to DeFi raises a theoretical tension. In <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Mehrling (2013)</ref> and Bell (1998), the hierarchy's apex is sovereign power: the state's ability to levy taxes and enforce legal tender creates the ultimate demand for base money. In DeFi, no sovereign exists. What, then, grounds the hierarchy?</p><p>Three mechanisms substitute imperfectly. First, protocol utility: ETH derives its base money status from its indispensability as the gas token required for every Ethereum transaction, generating persistent nonspeculative demand analogous to the Chartalist account of taxdriven demand for fiat money (Bell 2001). Second, smart contract guarantees partially replace institutional trust: protocols operate through auditable bytecode whose execution is deterministic, reducing (though not eliminating) the discretionary risk present in traditional intermediation. Third, liquidity depth: basetier tokens benefit from deep, selfreinforcing order books that make them the natural unit of account and medium of exchange within DeFi.</p><p>These mechanisms also illuminate how par settlement <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Mehrling 2011)</ref> works differ ently at each tier of the DeFi hierarchy. WETH maintains par with ETH through direct, mechanical redemption. stETH maintains par with ETH through secondary market liquidity-which can break under stress, as the 6% discount in June 2022 demonstrated. aWETH maintains par with WETH through overcollateralization and protocol solvency. The progressive weakening of par mechanisms at higher tiersfrom mechanical redemption to marketdependent liquidity to solvencydependent claims-provides a complementary interpretation for the structural distance discount.</p><p>Deeply nested tokens attract fewer borrowers (who prefer to borrow simpler, more liquid collateral), depressing utilization rates and the algorithmically determined lending yields that dominate upper tiers.</p><p>The SVB crisis starkly exposes the limits of these grounding mechanisms. When Circle revealed its $3.3 billion exposure to Silicon Valley Bank, USDC depegged to $0.87, and the shock cascaded through the hierarchy: aUSDC broke par with USDC, which had itself broken par with USD. The episode demonstrates that the DeFi hier archy, despite its aspirations to autonomy, ultimately rests on a foundation that extends into traditional banking <ref type="bibr">(Aldasoro et al. 2023)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3">Limitations</head><p>Endogeneity. Despite saturated controls and randomization inference, we cannot fully rule out confounding. A fully causal design would require instrumental variables or exogenous shocks to graph structure, neither of which is available in our setting.</p><p>Data coverage. Only 46.5% of aggregate DeFi TVL is independently verifiable on chain <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Saggese et al. 2025)</ref>, and our balancesheet heuristic for tier assignment covers 93% of the panel but may miss nonstandard tokens. Offchain "points" programs (EigenLayer, ether.fi, Ethena) are invisible in our data and disproportionately accrue to highertier positions, meaning the embedded yield correction is conservative.</p><p>Recursive leverage. Our framework tracks tokentype derivations but not within type quantity leverage from depositborrowredeposit looping, which would require positionlevel onchain data.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.4">Policy Implications</head><p>For regulators, the layering multiplier provides a readily computable macropruden For investors, the embedded yield correction has a practical implication: a Tier 3 token's reported yield systematically understates total return, because it omits the staking and lending yields accumulated at upstream tiers. At the same time, the struc tural distance discount of approximately 1.4 pp per hop means that pools farther from base assets earn genuinely lower marginal yields, and this discount widens during crises when upstream dependency risk becomes salient. Investors should thus evaluate positions not only by reported APY but by their full derivation chain.</p><p>For protocol designers, hierarchical position clarifies systemic footprint. A protocol that issues Tier 3 tokens sits atop a longer chain of dependencies than one issuing Tier 1 tokens, and this position should inform the design of circuit breakers, collateral requirements, and governance mechanisms.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusion</head><p>The token hierarchy is not a measurement artifact to be filtered away but the orga nizing principle through which composable protocols create, transform, and propagate risk. A growing body of work treats derivative layering as noise-double counting to be corrected so that "true" TVL can be recovered. We argue the opposite: the layering is the credit structure. Asking "how much double counting exists?" is akin to asking "how much money multiplier exists?" in banking-the answer is not a correction factor but a structural description of how claims propagate through intermediation chains.</p><p>The 4.7× multiplier is a measure of systemwide leverage with direct implications for cascade risk.</p><p>Because DeFi lacks deposit insurance and a lender of last resort, hierarchical risk gradients that are compressed in insured banking systems become directly observable.</p><p>The structural distance discount and its crisistime widening offer an empirical win dow into how credit hierarchies price risk absent public backstops; the embedded yield correction, in turn, shows that protocollevel reporting-however transparent each protocol may be-systematically understates the dependency structure visible only at the topology level. The Token Graph and layering multiplier offer a step toward the systemlevel DeFi monitoring that the FSB and IMF have identified as a priority but note remains hampered by data gaps and the absence of standardized methodology <ref type="bibr">(Financial Stability Board 2023, International Monetary Fund and</ref><ref type="bibr">Financial Stability Board 2023)</ref>.</p><p>The Token Graph updates with every onchain transaction, opening directions that static balancesheet data cannot support: stresstesting the hierarchy by simulating the removal of individual protocols, testing whether changes in the multiplier anticipate crisis episodes, and examining whether tier position predicts the order in which tokens break par during stress.</p><p>pointing to token 𝑥. The tier of a token is the length of the shortest directed path from any base asset in 𝐺 deriv :</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">Tier(𝑥) = { 0 if 𝑥 ∈ 𝒳︀ base 1 + min 𝑒∈ In(𝑥) Tier(src(𝑒)) if In(𝑥) ≠ ∅ -1 otherwise (unmapped)<label>(5)</label></formula><p>where src(𝑒) denotes the source token of edge 𝑒. The minimization selects the parent with the lowest tier among all derivation edges pointing to 𝑥. Tokens whose parents are all unmapped (Tier = -1) remain unmapped; this is equivalent to BFS from 𝒳︀ base through 𝐺 deriv , as implemented in Section A.6, where unreached tokens receive Tier(𝑥) = -1.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A.4 Layering Multiplier</head><p>The systemwide layering multiplier at time 𝑡 is:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">LM(𝑡) = TVL mapped 𝑡 TVL Tier 0 (𝑡)<label>(6)</label></formula><p>where TVL mapped(𝑡) = ∑ 𝑃 ∈𝒫︀ TVL(𝑃 , 𝑡) is total mapped TVL across all protocols and TVL Tier 0 (𝑡) is the TVL attributable to Tier 0 tokens-the value of base assets locked in DeFi protocols, not their total market capitalization. As discussed in Section 2, the multiplier captures all forms of derivative layering-format conversion and claim creation (via staking and lending)-and is thus broader than the traditional banking money multiplier, which reflects only lendingbased intermediation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A.5 Multiplier Decomposition by Protocol Type</head><p>We allocate the excess layering multiplier (LM(𝑡) -1) to protocol types proportion ally to their share of tierincreasing edge TVL. This is a descriptive accounting decomposition, not a causal attribution. For each tierincreasing edge (𝑥, 𝑦) ∈ ℰ︀ deriv with Tier(𝑦) = Tier(𝑥) + 1, we classify the mediating protocol into category 𝑘 ∈ {Lending, Staking, DEX, Other} and compute each type's share of total edge TVL:</p><p>𝑤 𝑘 (𝑡) = ∑ (𝑥,𝑦): type(𝑃 𝑥→𝑦 )=𝑘 TVL edge (𝑥, 𝑦, 𝑡) ∑ (𝑥,𝑦) TVL edge (𝑥, 𝑦, 𝑡)</p><p>The protocoltype contribution to the excess multiplier is then:</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">ΔLM 𝑘 (𝑡) = 𝑤 𝑘 (𝑡) ⋅ (LM(𝑡) -1)<label>(8)</label></formula><p>so that ∑ 𝑘 ΔLM 𝑘 = LM -1. For multihop paths (e.g., ETH → stETH via Lido → astETH via Aave), each hop contributes independently to its respective protocol type's edge TVL share. This approach avoids the poollevel attribution difficulty where a pool's symbol determines its tier but not its economic function (e.g., an Aave WETH pool's symbol maps to Tier 1 via WETH, yet its economic function is lending).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A.6 Tier Assignment Algorithm</head><p>The complete procedure for discovering the token hierarchy from poollevel data is as follows:</p><p>Algorithm 1:</p><p>Token Hierarchy Discovery Input: Pool data 𝒟︀ with input/output token mappings; protocol categories 𝒞︀ Output: Tier assignment 𝜏 : 𝒳︀ → {0, 1, 2, …} ∪ {-1} 1. Build Full Graph. For each pool 𝑝 ∈ 𝒟︀, for each valid token pair (𝑥 in , 𝑥 out ) with 𝑥 in ≠ 𝑥 out , add edge (𝑥 in , 𝑥 out ) with TVL weight to graph 𝐺 full . 2. Build Derivation Graph. Starting from 𝐺 full : (a) remove edges from trading protocols (DEX, Derivatives, Bridges, etc.) via 𝒞︀ (b) filter crosscollateral edges: if output token appears among inputs, suppress edges to it (c) remove basetobase lending edges where both tokens are significant base assets (outdegree ≥ 5, source TVL ≥ $10M) (d) for wrapping pairs, reverse to creation direction using known DeFi prefixes (e) apply Tier 0 protection: remove nonnamerelated incoming edges to strong basetoken candidates (f) add explicit CDP minting edges for protocols absent from yield data (g) add synthetic edges via composite name parsing, prefix stripping, and matching Outlier Treatment Tier Coeff. SE 𝑅 2 Baseline (APY &lt; 100) -0.520 (0.290) 0.059 Winsorize 1st/99th -0.504 (0.285) 0.061 Winsorize 2nd/98th -0.475 (0.276) 0.064 Winsorize 5th/95th -0.362 (0.237) 0.074 Trimmed 1st/99th -0.407 (0.255) 0.061</p><p>Table 8 | Tier Coefficient Under Alternative Outlier Treatments (Column 4 specification). 𝑁 = 2,036,562 for winsorization; 𝑁 = 2,016,197 for trimming.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>C Winsorization Robustness</head><p>Our baseline specification filters APY to [0, 100). Table <ref type="table">8</ref> reports the tier coefficient under alternative outlier treatments: winsorization (clipping at given percentiles) and trimming (dropping observations outside the range).</p><p>The coefficient ranges from -0.36 to -0.52 pp across all treatments, confirming the negative tier-yield association is not driven by extreme observations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>D Survivorship Bias</head><p>If highertier pools exit the sample disproportionately, survivorship bias could inflate the gradient.</p><p>Pool attrition. Only 75 of 4,905 pools (1.5%) exit before the observation period ends.</p><p>Exit rates are uniformly low across tiers (range: 0.0-1.8%). There is no significant corre lation between tier and exit (𝑟 = -0.88, 𝑝 = 0.12). During the three crises, zero pool exits occurred.</p><p>Balanced panel test.</p><p>Table 9 restricts to pools surviving at least 6 or 12 months. Longlived (-0.48 pp) and mediumlived (-0.55 pp) subsamples are consistent with the fullsample estimate (-0.52 pp). The FTXspanning subsample yields -0.32 pp, Sample Pools Tier Coeff. SE 𝑅 2 Full sample 4,905 -0.520 (0.290) 0.059 Longlived (≥ 12 mo) 2,487 -0.480 (0.331) 0.056 Mediumlived (≥ 6 mo) 3,441 -0.546 (0.300) 0.059 Spanning FTX crisis 651 -0.325 (0.603) 0.034</p><p>Table 9 | Survivorship Robustness: Tier Coefficient Across Balanced Panel Definitions. All use the Table 4 Column (4) specification.</p><p>directionally consistent though insignificant due to the smaller sample. Survivorship bias does not materially affect results.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>E Placebo Test</head><p>We conduct randomization inference by permuting tier labels across pools 1,000 times, preserving withinpool correlation, and reestimating the baseline specification for each permutation <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Eggers et al. 2024)</ref>. This nonparametric approach does not rely on asymptotic assumptions that may be unreliable in DeFi data <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Hagemann 2020)</ref>.</p><p>For the tier model, placebo coefficients center around zero (mean = -0.016, SD = 0.30); the actual baseline coefficient of -0.52 lies at the 4.4th percentile of the permu tation distribution (onesided 𝑝 = 0.044). For graph distance under full FE, the actual coefficient of -1.86 is highly significant (𝑝 &lt; 0.001). The permutation test confirms both channels at conventional significance levels.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>F Graph Distance Regressions</head><p>Table <ref type="table">10</ref> reports graph distance regressions with progressively saturated controls.</p><p>Graph distance is the shortestpath length in integer hops from each pool's primary token to the nearest Tier 0 token; it is available for 93% of the panel (𝑁 = 1,900,190, 4,159 pools). The excluded 7% (𝑁 = 136,372, 746 pools) consists of tokens without a derivation path to Tier 0; these are predominantly idiosyncratic pools whose exclusion, if anything, biases the coefficient toward zero.</p><p>Each hop is associated with -2.15 to -1.31 pp lower APY across all specifications (Columns 1-4). Chain fixed effects produce the largest attenuation (Column 3: -1.31 pp), suggesting some of the graph distance effect reflects chainlevel differences.</p><p>Column (5) is the joint specification including both tier (+1.18 pp, 𝑝 = 0.02) and graph distance (-2.75 pp, 𝑝 &lt; 0.001), confirming the two opposing channels identified in Section 4.3.</p><p>(1)</p><p>(2) (3) (4) (5) Baseline 1. Prot. FE 1. Chain FE 1. Both FE Joint Graph dist. -2.150 * * * -2.169 * * * -1.305 * * * -1.862 * * * -2.747 * * * (0.303) (0.388) (0.325) (0.390) (0.569) Tier 1.182 * * (0.489) Controls Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes Time FE Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes Protocoltype FE No Yes No Yes Yes Chain FE No No Yes Yes Yes Observations 1,900,190 1,900,190 1,900,190 1,900,190 1,900,190 𝑅 2 0.012 0.034 0.036 0.059 0.059</p><p>Table 10 | Panel Regression: APY on Graph Distance. Controls: log(TVL), stablecoin indicator. Sample restricted to pools with mapped graph distance (93% of full panel). Column (5) includes both tier and graph distance. Poolclustered SEs. * * * 𝑝 &lt; 0.01, * * 𝑝 &lt; 0.05. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Bibliography</head></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Fig. 1 |</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Fig.1| Token transformation in a lending protocol. The protocol accepts Tier 1 tokens as deposits and issues Tier 2 receipt tokens.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Fig. 2 Fig. 2 |</head><label>22</label><figDesc>Fig.2shows the dominant tokens at each tier. ETH accounts for the majority of Tier 0 value, followed by the major stablecoins (USDC, USDT, USDS). At Tier 1, liquid staking derivatives-stETH and its wrapped variant wstETH-dominate, alongside Morpho and Sky vault tokens derived from stablecoins. Tier 2 is headed by Aave receipt tokens (aWBTC, aWSTETH, aWETH) and EtherFi's restaking wrapper (WEETH), reflecting the "stake then lend" pattern we examine below. The sharp drop in individual token</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Fig. 3 Fig. 3 |</head><label>33</label><figDesc>Fig.3shows the evolution of DeFi's hierarchical structure. Panel (a) reveals that despite absolute TVL volatility through successive crises, the relative tier distribution remains stable: Tier 0 and Tier 1 consistently account for 75-85% of mapped TVL.Although the tier labels in this figure are assigned from the fullsample graph, indepen dent persnapshot discovery yields nearidentical assignments from 2023 onward (&gt; 95% agreement; Section B.1), confirming that the stability reflects genuine architectural</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Fig. 4 |</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Fig. 4 | TimeVarying Yield Gradient Across the Token Hierarchy. (a) Monthly tier coefficients from rolling regressions with 95% confidence intervals; vertical lines mark major events. (b) Tier coefficients by market regime.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><figDesc>Fig. 4 examines this prediction. Panel (a) plots monthly tier coef ficients from rolling regressions with 95% confidence intervals, showing substantial temporal variation. Panel (b) compares market regimes directly: the tier coefficient rises from 0.61 pp during normal periods to 1.62 pp during the SVB crisis and 1.45</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><figDesc>tial metric (Aramonte et al. 2021). Its swing from 2.1 × in early 2024 to 4.7 × by late 2025 mirrors the kind of leverage cycle that traditional banking regulators monitor through capital ratios and reserve requirements. A rising multiplier signals growing leverage; a sharp contraction signals a deleveraging cascade in progress.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><figDesc>Aldasoro I, Mehrling P, Neilson DH (2023) On par: A Money View of stablecoins Anadu K, Azar PD, Begenau J, et al (2024) Runs and Flights to Safety: Are Stablecoins the New Money Market Funds? Aramonte S, Huang W, Schrimpf A (2021) DeFi Risks and the Decentralisation Illusion. BIS Quarterly Review 21-36 Auer R, Haslhofer B, Kitzler S, et al (2024) The Technology of Decentralized Finance (DeFi). Digital Finance 6:55-95. https://doi.org/10.1007/s42521023000888 Augustin P, ChenZhang R, Shin D (2022) Reaching for Yield in Decentralized Financial Markets Badev A, Watsky C (2023) Interconnected DeFi: Ripple Effects from the Terra Collapse Bell S (1998) The hierarchy of money. The Jerome Levy Economics Institute WP Bell S (2001) The Role of the State and the Hierarchy of Money. Cambridge Journal of Economics 25:149-163. https://doi.org/10.1093/cje/25.2.149</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table 2 |</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Descriptive Statistics by Hierarchy Tier. APY in percentage points; Stable % is share of stablecoindenominated pools.where 𝛼 𝑡 represents time fixed effects and Stablecoin 𝑖 absorbs the baserate differential between fiatlinked and cryptonative pools, which reflect distinct yieldgenerating</figDesc><table><row><cell>indicator, protocol type (Lending, Liquid Staking, DEX, Yield Aggregator, Other), and</cell></row><row><cell>blockchain. Tier assignments are timeinvariant, derived from the fullsample token</cell></row><row><cell>graph; Section B.1 verifies that persnapshot discovery yields nearly identical assign</cell></row><row><cell>ments from 2023 onward. Table 2 reports summary statistics by tier.</cell></row><row><cell>To test Hypothesis 1, we estimate:</cell></row></table><note><p>The resulting panel comprises 2.0 million observations across 4,905 pools. Tier 1 accounts for 61% of observations, Tier 0 for 28%, Tier 2 for 11%, and Tier 3 for 1%.</p><p>For each pool 𝑖 in month 𝑡, we observe APY 𝑖,𝑡 , tier Tier 𝑖 , TVL 𝑖,𝑡 , a stablecoin APY 𝑖,𝑡 = 𝛽 ⋅ Tier 𝑖 + 𝛾 ⋅ log(TVL 𝑖,𝑡 ) +𝛿 ⋅ Stablecoin 𝑖 + 𝛼 𝑡 + 𝜀 𝑖,𝑡</p><p>(1) regimes (borrowing demand versus staking rewards). Under Hypothesis 1, we expect 𝛽 &gt; 0.</p><p>We progressively add blockchain fixed effects and protocoltype fixed effects (Lend ing, Liquid Staking, DEX, Yield Aggregator, Other). Protocol type is plausibly a mediator rather than a confounder: the Money View predicts that different intermediary types specialize at different depths as Table3</p><p>confirms, so controlling for protocol type may absorb the mechanism through which the hierarchy operates. The most saturated specification includes both: APY 𝑖,𝑡 = 𝛽 ⋅ Tier 𝑖 + 𝛾 ⋅ log(TVL 𝑖,𝑡 ) +𝛿 ⋅ Stablecoin 𝑖 + 𝛼 𝑡 + 𝜇 𝑝 + 𝜈 𝑐 + 𝜀 𝑖,𝑡</p></note></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>The author thanks seminar participants at the <rs type="institution">Cambridge Centre for Alternative Finance</rs> for helpful comments.</p></div>
			</div>			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Declarations</head><p>• Funding: This research received no specific grant from any funding agency in the public, commercial, or notforprofit sectors.</p><p>• Conflict of interest: The author declares no competing interests.</p><p>• Data availability: The datasets analyzed during the current study are available from DefiLlama (<ref type="url" target="https://defillama.com">https://defillama.com</ref>). Processed data and replication code are available from the corresponding author upon reasonable request.</p><p>• Code availability: Replication code is available from the corresponding author upon reasonable request.</p><p>• CRediT author statement: Wenbin Wu: Conceptualization, Methodology, Software, Formal analysis, Data curation, Visualization, Writing -original draft, Writingreview &amp; editing.</p><p>• Declaration of generative AI in the writing process: During the preparation of this work the author used generative AI tools in order to improve language and readability. After using these tools, the author reviewed and edited the content as needed and takes full responsibility for the content of the publication.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A Formal Definitions</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A.1 Token Contracts and Operations</head><p>Let 𝒳︀ denote the set of all tokens in the DeFi ecosystem, and let 𝒫︀ denote the set of all protocols. For each protocol 𝑃 𝑖 ∈ 𝒫︀, we define:</p><p>• 𝑋 𝐿 (𝑃 𝑖 ) ⊆ 𝒳︀: the set of tokens that protocol 𝑃 𝑖 accepts as inputs (lockable tokens)</p><p>• 𝑋 𝐺 (𝑃 𝑖 ) ⊆ 𝒳︀: the set of tokens that protocol 𝑃 𝑖 generates as outputs • 𝑋 𝐶 (𝑃 𝑖 , 𝑡) ⊆ 𝑋 𝐿 (𝑃 𝑖 ): the set of tokens currently locked in protocol 𝑃 𝑖 at time 𝑡 The Total Value Locked for protocol 𝑃 𝑖 at time 𝑡 is:</p><p>where 𝑞 𝑖 (𝑥, 𝑡) is the quantity of token 𝑥 held by protocol 𝑃 𝑖 at time 𝑡, and 𝑣(𝑥, 𝑡) is the USD price of token 𝑥 at time 𝑡.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A.2 Token Graph and Derivation Graph</head><p>The full token graph represents all token transformation relationships across the ecosystem:</p><p>where ℰ︀ full ⊆ 𝒳︀ × 𝒳︀ × 𝒫︀ is the set of directed edges. An edge (𝑥 1 , 𝑥 2 , 𝑃 𝑖 ) ∈ ℰ︀ full indi cates that protocol 𝑃 𝑖 accepts token 𝑥 1 and generates token 𝑥 2 , i.e., 𝑥 1 ∈ 𝑋 𝐿 (𝑃 𝑖 ) and 𝑥 2 ∈ 𝑋 𝐺 (𝑃 𝑖 ).</p><p>The derivation graph 𝐺 deriv = (𝒳︀, ℰ︀ deriv ) is obtained from 𝐺 full by removing trading protocols, crosscollateral edges, and basetobase lending edges, and adding CDP minting edges and synthetic namecontainment edges, as detailed in Section 3 and Section A.6. Tier assignment operates on 𝐺 deriv .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A.3 Tier Assignment</head><p>Let 𝒳︀ base ⊂ 𝒳︀ denote the set of base assets (Tier 0 tokens), identified as described in Section A.6. Let In(𝑥) = {𝑒 ∈ ℰ︀ deriv : tgt(𝑒) = 𝑥} denote the set of derivation edges Call the result 𝐺 deriv . </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Discover</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A.7 Circular Dependencies</head><p>The 79 cycles identified in Section 3 arise predominantly from bidirectional lending (e.g., a protocol accepting both WETH and aWETH). Excluding the trivial ETH ↔︎ WETH wrapper, cycleinvolved TVL is $21.7M. Our BFS resolves these by assigning the minimum tier from the shortest path to Tier 0.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>B Tier Assignment Sensitivity</head><p>We vary the minimum outdegree (2, 3, 5, 7, 10) and TVL threshold ($0, $100K, $1M, $10M, $100M), yielding 25 configurations, and compute Jaccard similarity of each Tier 0 set against the baseline.  Core tokens (ETH, BTC, SOL, USDC, USDT) appear as Tier 0 in all 25 configurations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Min. out-deg</head><p>For nearby configurations (outdegree ∈ {2, 3, 5}, TVL ∈ {$0, $100𝐾, $1𝑀 }), Jaccard similarity exceeds 0.80. Sensitivity increases at extremes (outdegree ≥ 10, TVL ≥ $100 M), though even extreme configurations retain core tokens. We also reclassify econom ically ambiguous tokens <ref type="bibr">(stETH, wstETH, rETH, DAI)</ref> between Tier 0 and Tier 1; the main tier coefficient is qualitatively stable.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>B.1 Temporal Stability of Tier Assignments</head><p>Our baseline uses timeinvariant tier assignments derived from the fullsample token graph. To verify that this does not impose artificial stability, we rerun the complete tier discovery algorithm independently on each quarterly snapshot from Q1 2022 through Q4 2025, restricting to pools with nonzero TVL at each date.  </p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Surprising Irrelevance of TotalValueLocked on Cryptocurrency Returns</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Brigida</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.econlet.2025.112673</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.econlet.2025.112673"/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Economics Letters</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">257</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">112673</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2025">2025</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Anatomy of a Stablecoin's Failure: The TerraLuna Case</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Briola</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Vidaltomás</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Aste</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.frl.2022.103358</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.frl.2022.103358"/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Finance Research Letters</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">103358</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2023">2023</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Why DeFi Lending? Evidence from Aave V2 DefiLlama</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Cornelli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Gambacorta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Garratt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Reghezza</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://github.com/DefiLlama/DefiLlamaAdapters/discussions/434"/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">) DefiLlama: DeFi TVL Aggregator</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022">2024. 2024. 2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>DoubleCounting Policy</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Placebo Tests for Causal Inference</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Eggers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Tuñón</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Dafoe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/ajps.12818</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/ajps.12818"/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Journal of Political Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">68</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1106" to="1121"/>
			<date type="published" when="2024">2024</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Financial Stability Risks of Decentralised Finance</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Etherscan ; Gorton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="//etherscan.io/tokensFinancial"/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">University of Chicago Law Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">90</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="909" to="971"/>
			<date type="published" when="2023">2024. 2023. 2023</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Stability Board Token Tracker. https: Taming Wildcat Stablecoins</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Placebo Inference on Treatment Effects When the Number of Clusters Is Small</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Hagemann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.jeconom.2019.04.011</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jeconom.2019.04.011"/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Econometrics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">213</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="190" to="209"/>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">IMFFSB Synthesis Paper: Policies for CryptoAssets</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>International Monetary Fund, Financial Stability Board</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2023">2023</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Disentangling Decentralized Finance (DeFi) Compositions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Kitzler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Victor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Saggese</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Haslhofer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3532857</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3532857"/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACM Transactions on the Web</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="26"/>
			<date type="published" when="2023">2023</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">While Stability Lasts: A Stochastic Model of Non custodial Stablecoins</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Klagesmundt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Minca</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/mafi.12357</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/mafi.12357"/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Mathematical Finance</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="943" to="981"/>
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Anatomy of a Run: The Terra Luna Crash Luo Y</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Makarov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">;</forename><surname>Schoar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Feng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Tasca</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>arXiv</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Piercing the veil of TVL: DeFi reappraised</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023">2023. 2024</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The inherent hierarchy of money</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Mehrling</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Social Fairness and Economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="409" to="419"/>
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The New Lombard Street: How the Fed Became the Dealer of Last Resort</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Mehrling</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
			<publisher>Princeton University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Princeton, NJ</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Credit Theory of AntiCredit Money: How the Cryptocurrency Sphere Turned into a Shadow Banking System</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Olk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Miebs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/09692290.2025.2476738</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/09692290.2025.2476738"/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Review of International Political Economy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1414" to="1441"/>
			<date type="published" when="2025">2025</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Liquidations: DeFi on a KnifeEdge</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Perez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Werner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Livshits</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Financial Cryptography and Data Security (FC 2021)</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Berlin, Heidelberg</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="457" to="476"/>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Estimating Standard Errors in Finance Panel Data Sets: Comparing Approaches</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Petersen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1093/rfs/hhn053</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1093/rfs/hhn053"/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Review of Financial Studies</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="435" to="480"/>
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Shadow Banking: The Money View</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Pozsar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Towards Verifiability of Total Value Locked (TVL) in Decentralized Finance Schär F (2021) Decentralized Finance: On Blockchain and Smart ContractBased Financial Markets</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Saggese</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Fröwis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Kitzler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.20955/r.103.153-74</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.20955/r.103.15374"/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Federal Reserve Bank of St Louis Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">103</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="153" to="174"/>
			<date type="published" when="2025">2025</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">DeXposureFM: A Graph Foundation Model for Forecasting InterProtocol Credit Exposure in Decentralized Finance</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Shu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Ibikunle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J ;</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Werner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Perez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Gudgeon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 4th ACM Conference on Advances in Financial Technologies (AFT '22)</title>
		<meeting>the 4th ACM Conference on Advances in Financial Technologies (AFT '22)<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2022">2026. 2022</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="30" to="46"/>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>SoK: Decentralized Finance (DeFi)</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">DeXposure: A Dataset and Benchmarks for Inter protocol Credit Exposure in Decentralized Financial Networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Qian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Lui</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.48550/arXiv.2511.22314</idno>
		<idno>arXiv:251122314</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.48550/arXiv.2511.22314"/>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2025">2025</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>